Guide to the William Morris Wallpaper Samples, 1864 - 1896
Department of Special Collections
William Morris Wallpaper Samples,
1864 - 1896
Special Collections M0936
Morris, William, 1834-1896
36 items
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of William Morris
Scope and Content
Includes one design by William's daughter, May Morris, called Honeysuckle, 1883. Many samples are named and dated on their backs.
Access terms
Morris, May; Arts and crafts movement; Decoration and ornament--History--19th century; Wallpaper
Container List
- Acorn (2) 1879 (Folder 1)
- Compton, the last design 1896 (Folder 2)
- Honeysuckle, one of the very few by William Morris's daughter, May Morris. c. 1883 (Folder 3)
- Sunflower (2) 1879 (Folder 4)
- Wilow (2) 1874 (Folder 5)
- Pomegranate 1864 (Folder 6)
- Bird and anemone (3) 1882 (Folder 7)
- Norwich 1889 (Folder 8)
- Bachelors Button (2) 1892 (Folder 9)
- Marigold 1875 (Folder 10)
- Chrysanthemum 1877 (Folder 11)
- Vine 1873 (Folder 12)
- The Planet (2) n.d. (Folder 13)
- Wild tulip, (2 slightly different) 1884 (Folder 14)
- unnamed, some of these may be single color trials (13) n.d. (Folder 15)